Okay, I might have lied.
$3,996,857.18. But by the time this
video is edited,
that would've surpassed $4 million.
And I thought this would make a great
opportunity to say where is it, where it
goes, where I've invested it.
Was it worth it?
How I started it,
how I did it without sales calls, upsells,
email marketing, sales
process, hires.
Because rewind two years ago,
or maybe just over,
I had no interest in starting this
business. And I'll tell you the truth.
When you look at athletes,
sometimes we can see who's in the best
shape, and we can
try and think we know who knows the most.
Think that person must know so much about
training and nutrition, and the reality
is they've just got good genetics.
There's a similar thing in the business
field where we kind of look at people that
have the most money and think, "Oh my God,
they must know so much about business."
It took me quite a while to realize
that some people are just blaggers.
And where I was on a mission in the
fitness industry to eradicate all the BS,
I
can't do the same in the business world.
So first things first, where's
that $4 million? I haven't got it.
$4 million revenue does not mean $4
million in your pocket.
So for any of you that
are about to embark on this journey
that I just did over the
last few years,
whether it's selling your first course,
doing B2B or whatever,
you're not going to keep all of that.
I roughly get to keep about 55% of the
revenue that comes in monthly.
45% is gone. We've got paid ads, which
are a big part of
revenue in these B2B online businesses,
and a lot of us, just like I did then,
flash our revenue,
but we don't flash our costs.
The one metric that's really important
is something called ROAS, return on ad
spend, and we track
that very aggressively.
Then I've got a business partner
that operate all the infrastructure.
They get 10% of any money we make.
Not profit, rev.
And then out of that 55%,
my manager gets his cut, which is 20%,
which can seem
like a lot, but it's not.
For what he does, he could have more.
He could be siphoning more.
And people don't believe me
when I say this.
He has all the money. It goes to him,
and he puts out all the fires,
he deals with
everything that needs to be dealt with,
and then whatever's left at the end of the
month, he sends me. So if you said,
"James,
how much money have you got?" I know
because he told me this morning. But
if he is siphoning away cash from me, he's
doing a bloody good job.
So then you're like, "Okay, cool. 55%.
Sweet.
You've got over $2 million." Yes.
Then the taxman comes along,
and Australia,
it's 47%. So by the time you pull out
that $2 million,
you're left with a million.
Which is still nice. Don't get me wrong.
This is US dollars as well.
So you're like, "Cool.
You've got $1 million.
Where'd you spend it?" The only investment
I really have is in NuTonic.
I don't have any stocks,
I don't have any shares,
don't have any ETFs, don't have
any crypto.
I put hundreds of thousands of dollars
into NuTonic, and that's kind of
my way out of here.
But I've also had to invest it into this
studio,
which cost about $35,000, $40,000 US.
Declan, who's sat out there,
he's full-time.
And I go through some of the other really
important hires in a second.
But one question I want to pose before I
teach you the structure of the business
and what I built,
and I'm doing this so you can copy it.
I've got friends who
are kind of wanting to move into this
business-to-business
space, and they don't know where to start.
So this video's kind of for them.
Now, is it worth it?
Something I need to get off my chest is
if you'd met me two,
three years ago, I'd made good money,
but not crazy money.
Not Porsche 911 GT3 money. But my life
was chill.
When I was just running a fitness
business,
I had to make a piece of content a day,
write an email, have a nap, train jujitsu.
My life was amazing. I lived in Bondi.
I had a very stress-free life,
living well within my means.
I will admit now my life
is a lot more stressed.
I am a lot more tired.
I'm spinning a lot of plates. Arguably,
although the most successful
period of my life, it
is a daily sometimes battle to have to
remind myself how lucky I am.
With everything I'm going to teach you,
you must be
warned. To operate at this level,
you will need to develop a
small form of mental illness because to
grind every day.
The sales, Declan said before,
"Do the sales just come in?" I'm like,
"No, I have
to fight for every single one every single
week." If I take my foot off the gas
just for one month, revenue halves.
But for me, is it worth it?
Let's look at that at the end.
First of all, let's go downstairs.
Let's look into a little bit more of it.
If I was you starting out,
I would start with calls.
So before you build anything, the issue
is you might build something that people
don't want. So instead,
put some time into your diary
and sell your time for money.
You might start off $200 US
if you're in business-to-business,
maybe $100 US
if you're in some other kind of thing.
And you could be a sleep consultant
teaching parents how to get their babies
to sleep.
You could be helping creators build on
social media.
You could be teaching people how to color
grade content.
Whatever it is, you just start off.
This is going to be a good video for you,
Declan. You're going to be learning it.
Just put calls in your diary. Now,
the reason being is you on every single
call you do with someone get to understand
their problems.
You get to understand their needs,
and you get to take a mental inventory of
the
things they struggle with.
So let's use color grading as a problem.
What would be a problem that they have?
Okay.
White balance, exposure, LUTs,
and then what else?
So Declan's getting on calls with people.
He's making $200 an hour.
Don't get any ideas.
You need to do this edit.
And he just finds out
that he keeps repeating himself.
White balance, exposure, LUTs, noise.
God, every time I get on these calls,
I just keep repeating myself.
So what he's going to do?
He's going to build.
Now, a lot of people think
that we create these online courses
because we're just
bros that want to make money online.
The reality is that we don't want to
repeat ourselves any longer.
If we can create assets that mean
that we can give people what they want,
if they
were going to pay $200 for it on a call,
they'd be way more likely to buy the
course for $99.
Then they can go through it at their own
time.
They can spend their time learning it,
whatever.
So are you saying
that before you build a course,
you want to make sure you've got
evidence of those particular issues in
your audience?
Yeah. So exactly that.
So what I'm saying is by being on
calls, you right now think this
is what they need help with.
But by doing calls with people,
they might say, "Declan, what is the best
platform to edit on?" And you say,
"It's DaVinci." They go,
"Everyone's told me
it's Premiere Pro." So you then add into
on the call why
DaVinci is really popular. Not only that.
By doing the call with the person
and getting that question,
not only have you
thought about that being something to
build, you've also thought,
"That's going to
be my next piece of content." So your next
video on YouTube goes up.
Why color graders must use DaVinci.
You A/B split test
that with why DaVinci's better than
Premiere Pro, and your third
title is why Premiere Pro
is terrible for color grading.
Now, whilst you are building
that into your course,
and you only found out that
that was a question from doing one-to-ones
with people, you now put out content on
the front end,
which then gets you more calls.
In the beginning, with
that content you put out on social media,
if you haven't got
anything to sell, your call to action
is just book a call.
But then when they go through to your
Calendly-
To book that call,
should we use a lead magnet,
or should we just-
You can just put a Calendly link.
And then some people might think it's a
sales
call, but then when they get there,
they have to pay the money.
So a call won't show up in your own
Calendly unless they paid the money.
Then someone's name's going to come
through like Trevor Whitehead has booked a
call Tuesday 4:00 PM,
$200 in your account. Sweet.
The great thing is then
when you jump on the call with
that person, you're like,
"Trevor, mate, how can I help?"
And whenever I've done these one-to-one
calls with
people, I literally just get on and go,
"How can I help?"
Would you want to put
that in the video itself and announce
that you've got that
option,
or just leave a link in the description?
Yeah. Call to action.
What we're saying there
is whilst you're going through
telling them why DaVinci is better, "Okay,
if this is too much for you, you can
just book in a call with me.
There's a link in the description."
And the beautiful
thing of that is your content might get
362 views, but you get two calls.
And now you've just made $400 from one
video that you've put out.
And with every call you're doing,
I can see your cogs moving in your head.
Yeah.
You're about to get edits coming back a
bit slower from this.
So through all of that
that you're building,
this list will increase to
the point that you're ready-
Know exactly what to build
... you'll know them inside out.
So once I've got something to build,
then how do I price it?
Okay, good question.
Once you know how to build,
how do you price it?
Imagine this as well.
The more you go on dates with women,
the more you get to
understand what women are like,
and the better you get at dating.
And you start to know their apprehensions.
You know the things they're worried about.
So for instance, this sounds really crass,
but once you've gone on a lot of dates
with girls,
you realize they don't want someone to try
and fuck them on a first
date. So through knowing that,
on the date, you just make it very clear.
By the way,
I used to joke with girls on dates.
Sorry, Tay, if you're watching this.
We'd sit down for a drink, I'd go,
"Just to let you know,
I'm not going to try and
fuck you tonight.
Let's just enjoy the evening." I'd go,
"If you try coming onto
me,
don't even treat me like a piece of meat.
I've got feelings."
And I would start the date by disarming
them because the whole
night that you're sat there having a drink
with them, they're thinking, "This guy
just wants to fuck me."
But by starting that,
by knowing their apprehensions
firsthand,
it disarms them. It makes them better.
And in content, in everything you do,
the more time you spend
talking to your clients,
the more you get to understand their
insecurities, their
fears, all of those things.
You might not even find out until you've
done 10 calls
with people why they want a color.
You might think it's because you want
their
content to look nice, but the truth
is they go,
"The only way my content can stick
out from other people
is through having better color grading."
And you go, "Cool."
Then what does that become, Declan?
Part of your hook and your pitch.
If you want to stick out amongst all your
competitors that have been editing longer
than you, there's one way you can do it,
proper color grading. See what I'm saying?
Zooming back to the pricing itself,
what would I base that on?
Okay. First things first, the hourly call,
as you get busy, will go up.
Okay.
How many calls on top of doing my editing
could you do a week? Three?
Probably one a day.
One a day? What are you doing, brother?
You're supposed to be working for me,
mate.
What do you mean one a day?
In the evening, like a 5:00 PM call
or something.
No. You're full-time, Declan.
Let's say three a week, right?
If you were three a week,
packed out for a few weeks,
you could just push that to
250. And eventually you just push it up.
So, about a year and a half ago, I
was doing calls for
$500. Now,
it sounds such a dickhead thing, even
$1,000, I'm like, "Oh." But demand
is what pushes that up.
So suddenly you're at 250.
But there's going to come a point where
even though
you're getting $250 for a call, you go,
"The issue is, if
you gave me an hour,
I could create a piece of content
which would sell me
seven of these." So you've now got a
decision.
Do I sell $350 worth of content in an
hour,
or do I jump on a call for 250?
And this is the predicament I'm in now.
This video will be filmed in under an
hour.
Someone could pay me $1,000 for an hour of
my time, but this video will make way
more than $1,000 to the business.
So you price yourself out.
Then there will come a point
that your content, and again,
that's only 350 in the
first week that you've launched it.
As you add more videos to your channel,
more backlog traffic creates
more evergreen content,
which sells more people to your course.
Some of the highest grossing videos we
have on this YouTube channel
are over a year
old,
and I'm talking the sales we made in the
last week are over a year old.
So soon you'll price yourself out,
and you will make your one-to-one call
something
crazy like $2,000. And it's not even
that you're worth $2,000, it's that you
don't want to do them. And if someone
is going to get you to do one,
you best get
paid well for it because you're taking
food off the plate from the other part of
the ecosystem.
So here's another question in terms of the
course and the offering itself.
I've heard a lot of people on YouTube
talking about how now that AI
is becoming a
big thing,
just having a course as information by
itself is not going to be as
valuable. Having a community
and having a Discord or a cohort
is going to be
more and more important.
Very good question. AI, I don't think
is as good as you think it is.
Not yet. It could be in a few years.
But also, imagine you said,
"I want to get in
shape," and AI said,
"I need you to exercise, do this,
this." You just don't listen
to it. When someone spends, and this
is the beauty of it.
If someone spends 2,000 hours on a call
with you, that money is wasted unless they
do all the things you talk about.
When you tell them to build an email list,
let's
say. Someone pays me $1,000, I go,
"Do that." If they do it,
it's worth the money. If they don't do it,
it isn't.
So when people pay AI, or don't pay AI,
or get AI to do it for free, they just
won't actually execute it.
The fact of the matter
is they need to pay someone to do
it.
We've all got injuries we know how to fix,
but we pay a physio, so we do it.
The community side,
we'll get onto in a second.
So that, as far as just calls, can
seem really basic, but it's not.
There's a lot to those calls.
So then I built out Business Manship 1.0.
You said about the community. There
was one other thing that we had, Discord.
Now, Discord is a place
that you can chat
and interact with people.
Even now,
I'll update people in the Discord with
what I'm up to and where to go and
assets to thing, blah, blah, blah.
We chat on a basis.
Here, I created, I think, five modules.
Each module had 10 lessons in it.
But we had the Discord,
and you spoke about the
community. The community was very good.
But some things we needed, feedback
and threads.
And some of the threads we put in there,
getting sales, closing sales, getting
leads, growing socials,
YouTube thumbnails, all of that.
You can see which threads are busiest.
So in yours, you might put exposure,
lighting, cameras,
editing software, MacBook, CPU,
whatever it is.
Then you will realize
that one of those threads becomes a lot
more popular than
everyone else. So the one that
was getting so much heat was
content. So everyone
was obsessed with content.
Now, most people
were obsessed with short-form content.
So-
You're almost saying
if you didn't have that community,
you wouldn't have that
information.
So it's so good for you to actually get
that market research.
Sometimes feedback
is what helps you know
if something's working.
Let me bring in something into case.
Fingering If you had a blindfold on
and muffs on so you couldn't hear
anything, you have no idea
if you're fingering good, right?
And the only way
that a young man gets better at fingering
is through trying out
some different stuff. The come to me,
right? The all of the different things.
Feeding the pony, whatever it is.
Then through the feedback you get,
and every
client is different, the feedback you get,
you go, "Oh, they like the scissor
kick," whatever. Right?
So the community is great for them because
they get that part of the community where
they-
You're almost leaving so much on the table
if you don't have a community
100%. Also, buyer's regret.
Do you know that?
The second someone buys something,
they regret it.
But if they've got that contact with you,
then it kind of re-enforces-
Me just saying,
"Welcome." One guy this morning has
joined, and-
Do you welcome everyone personally in
there?
Everyone. So today,
I haven't done the Discord,
but I've done the welcome channel.
Yeah.
Because if someone's just paid me-
Yeah
... $3,000,
they're getting a message from me within a
couple hours.
Yeah. Yeah.
One guy's got a rifle company doing
precision bits.
I was like, "Mate,
love this." Then there's another guy who's
just joined with a
really interesting business about tuning
cars. He's joined because I've got a GT3.
So I've already gone back to him. "What
is a tune?
Don't tell me that it improves fuel
mapping.
I don't know what fuel mapping is." So
Discord really helps you with the content.
I realized this content thread was hot,
so I created
Short-Form Content Mastery.
Could you potentially build out a
community on Discord before you have a
course?
So let's say-
No. Free communities, never.
Okay.
Because everyone in here
that asks me questions has already paid
me.
Okay.
So that comes after you've made the
course.
Don't be giving people your time for free,
because it just cheapens everything.
If you're going to help people do their
color grading for free on Discord, why the
fuck would they buy anything from you?
Yeah.
No,
I do not talk to anyone unless they get
paid.
The only
time I haven't done that is on Monday
when we did the livestream.
But I made $50,000 on the day.
So although I did the livestream for free,
I
didn't. I did it for $25,000 an hour.
Flex.
Don't ask for a pay rise, all right?
So because I haven't got that, remember?
We went through it in the first module.
I don't know where that money is.
One more thing while we're on the course
itself.
Would you say it's generally better to
script the entire course and plan it out,
or
can you kind of go off the cuff with that?
For this, yes. For this, not so much.
You should script, but don't be robotic.
Some people are quite robotic.
Script so you don't miss anything,
and there are different levels of
scripting.
You can script the whole thing word for
word, or-
Did you do that with your course?
Did you script the whole thing word for
word?
I did do the whole thing word for word,
but you'll notice that the script for this
video is a loose script.
We've only got one page of notes.
And we wrote that in about 10 minutes.
Not even.
Five.
Yeah.
Because I only put those notes there to
know, because I know all this stuff
anyway.
Yeah.
I just did it to make sure we had some
structure to it.
So I'll be honest with you,
Short-Form Content Mastery wasn't just
to help people with short-form content.
It was based off the insecurity
that the content modules in here weren't
good
enough.
And you only knew to build
that because the content thread
was going so hard.
So what I do is I give
that to everyone for free,
but I also sell it for
$99 to anyone on the outside.
So then we run paid ads for the business
mentorship,
but we also run paid ads for Short-Form
Content Mastery.
Good thing is,
we get some sales of people coming into
there.
We get an upsell rate of about 11%.
So 11% of the people that buy
that do that.
We sell about 20 of those a day.
So one person, two people, two
people a day join the mentorship from
that.
Now, as we went on, lead gen
was a hot topic, so
we did a lead magnet course.
Email marketing was a hot topic, so we
made Send Emails, Get Paid.
Do you think in certain niches it's easier
to have good lead magnets for?
Yes, but it depends.
Because I would say-
Fitness is a tough one.
Yeah, that's what I was thinking, fitness.
I've got a friend that's trying to do
tricking,
and it's very difficult for him to
make a decent lead magnet. But for me-
Tricking. What's tricking?
It's like acrobatics.
Okay. What does he do?
Can he do a backflip?
Yeah.
Then he should do...
Is doing a backflip hard?
If I spent a day with him,
could he teach me to do a backflip?
Oh, yeah.
Then he should probably make
that a lead magnet. What's his name?
Tony Tricks.
Tony,
make a fucking lead magnet on doing a
backflip, you lazy prick.
See, I came up with that in three seconds.
You're going to be like, "Oh,
can't make a lead magnet." Shut up.
Okay. So wherever there was something
that was lagging
behind. Another one was
that everyone in that fucking Discord,
65% of them are PTs.
So then I don't just create asset.
I thought, "If all of these are PTs,
I should probably make them a course
called PT
Starter Kit." Each one of these,
we call a satellite course.
They are an individual course.
I think this was $199,
or it might have been
$99, and I think this is $99.
And do you know what PTs are notoriously
shit at? Content.
So we actually put Short-Form Content
Mastery in the PT Starter
Kit. But that means that,
and the reason we did that, you go,
"Why would you do
that if it's $99?
You sell it for $99." Because the ads for
PTs are a
lot easier to make than ads for short-form
content.
So we actually use
that as a way to get personal trainers to
buy that, and then we
still get the 11% upsell.
Hope that's still recording, Declan.
This is some good stuff. Send Emails,
Get Paid was one,
but the lead magnet course,
you might remember, was free. Now,
all of these were given to people in the
mentorship,
and even the lead magnet course for free.
We get people inside the Discord saying,
"Thanks, mate.
Although it was already in the course,
the new course you made gave me the
reminder
that I needed." That lead magnet course we
got 9,000 leads for, so hopefully we'll
attribute some of those in some new sales.
So when you start whatever it
is you're doing,
you start with the course, you build
out iteration one.
But then what happened was,
as I made these courses,
I had an insecurity in my mind that was,
"I think these satellite courses are
better than the mentorship." So what do we
do?
We reformed the entire thing from the
ground up, completely rewrote the whole
course in February this year.
Took a whole month of planning from
posting on social
media. And then I also put the prices up.
Now, this side of things is scalable.
Whether there's 5,000 people in there,
10,000 people in there, whatever it is,
doesn't matter. This
is where the problem lies.
When the Discord gets too busy,
I'm left with only one thing to do.
What's that?
Raise prices.
Raise prices. The people
that got in at the beginning got in for
$800 US dollars.
Then it went to $1,000.
The current offer for Black Friday
is $2,500.
So I did a post this morning explaining to
people, that is two and a half times
what it was 12 months ago. And guess what,
fuckers?
It's going to be two
and a half times this in a year,
because this isn't even about
the people I'm helping.
This isn't even about the mentorship.
I want.
I'm always going to do the same amount of
work.
I'm always going to spend three hours a
day in the Discord. But do you know what?
I want more money for doing it. So
that in a year's time
is easily going to be
seven and a half grand. So
if you want to get in on a discount,
you could do it
today. If not,
we can continue with the rest of the
video.
But I swear to God I'll do
that just to prove a point.
A year's time, you'll go, "Oh, James,
I didn't actually think you're going to
put
your prices up."
That first year I spent in that Discord,
I was grossly underpaid.
Now I'm getting paid very well,
but next year I'm going to be throwing
money at
Declan. I'm going to be, "Declan,
here's a grand." Why? Because I can.
Another topic of community as well,
how important are the referrals?
We should do an affiliate.
We've been talking about doing an
affiliate, where
basically we give them 10% of whatever
they close. Referrals are really good.
Referrals are strong. It's better
if you can incentivize the people in that
Discord. They should be getting kickback.
We're working on it.
But yeah, people will just say it's good.
You've even made some hires from
that Discord as well, haven't you?
That's a good point, actually. So,
two hires I've made from my
Discord. So when I thought about staff
and people that I needed,
I actually already
knew some of them on a first-name basis.
I'd done calls with some of them.
And there was one guy called Cam,
who's in our Discord now. Imagine this.
Out of all those threads,
when I get there,
there's just this fucker, this Scottish
lad, helping people. And usually
when people help each other in the
Discord, I go,
"Oi, mate, is this your mentorship?" "No.
Shut up." But this guy called Cam,
every little thread he did, "Well,
that's pretty
good. Actually,
that's really good." I said,
"I completely agree with that." If
anything,
he was going into more detail than I was.
So I emailed Cam privately.
I went, "What are you doing?" He was like,
"Mate, I just enjoy this." "Do you want
a job? It's full-time now." Well,
by the time this video is going out, it's
full-time.
Fucking that's another load of money gone.
Let's say each week I can allocate 10
hours to the Discord.
That's going to be a certain amount of
clients.
And let's say we can onboard 10 clients on
any given week.
It's probably going to come from 1,000
emails.
We'll probably get 1,000 emails from
25,000 views.
Probably get 25,000 views from three
pieces of content that we can put out a
week. Now, the channel now is, I think,
at 50K, give or
take. Last year, it was about 7K.
That channel, if we
haven't got another silver play button in
a year's time, I'll be livid.
So all that happens there is,
as the channel doubles,
the content remains the
same, the 10 hours stays the same,
the 25,000 views
will probably go to 50,000.
The emails will go from 1,000 to
2,000, maybe even higher.
The clients remain at 10.
The only thing that we change
is twice the demand, twice the price.
Give me another year, might be at 300,000,
400,000.
Three pieces of content, 160,000 views,
10,000 emails,
10 clients. So really,
my focus for the next year is this.
This part remains all the same.
And as we get more expensive,
the beautiful thing
is you actually attract a different type
of client.
Right now, one of our biggest bottlenecks,
though it's a weird thing to say, is
we're too cheap for some businesses.
I was watching a video of Ali Abdaal
saying that he pays like 50 to 100K for
his
mentorships that he joins.
Just thinking like, "That's insane."
Some people-
That's like the price to entry that
when everyone in that mentorship you know
they're legit because the price
was so much.
So,
I'm not sure if I'm even supposed to
disclose this.
Did I tell you I got a black Amex?
I think so, yeah.
Yeah. So,
I now get to go to events with other
people that are
Centurions.
I get to rub shoulders with those people.
So if they go to invite me to some
orchestra thing, I'll probably go. Sure,
why?
Because I want to rub shoulders with other
people that have got black cards.
So there is that kind of thing,
we rub shoulders.
Also, Majes,
since we've doubled the price,
we're actually two and a half times the
price since last year.
Refund rates dropped off.
Time wasters dropped off.
Headaches dropped off.
Since doubling the price,
I've had half the headaches.
There's a golden rule.
Continue the rest upstairs.
Which brings me onto how you get people's
email
addresses from content in the first place.
Now, conveniently,
I have an array of lead magnets different
for people's needs.
So Declan, as aforementioned,
might have a white balance lead magnet,
an exposure
lead magnet, whatever.
I create a lead magnet based off the
courses, the satellite
courses there are. God,
I'm actually out of breath from running
upstairs.
So we have the landing page lead magnet,
which people get. They get that.
Afterwards,
they get an 11-day email automation.
Link to that in the description.
You can copy it.
There's also 30 Ways in 30 Days,
where people give me their email
address,
and I hit them with a bit of business
knowledge every day for 30 days.
And most people buy on day 19. Why?
I don't know.
Then I discovered a content bucket,
as we call it, where when I critique
and roast
people's content, although the views
are low, let's say 7,000 views a video, I
get hundreds of applications per video of
people that want their content critiqued.
Now, I can't do all of them,
but not only are people giving me their
contact
information so I can potentially critique
them, I just add them to the 30-day
automation. Now, what's crazy is,
so far there's three lead magnets.
We've got 30-Day Automation,
Anatomy of a Highly Converting Landing
Page, then we
have the Web Critique and Apply.
And all of those are in the description,
so you
can copy them. But the people
that go to the apply go through to the
same 30-day
automation,
but they double the attribution
and sales revenue.
So they make twice as much money. Why?
I don't know. I couldn't tell you.
I genuinely haven't got a clue.
So the next part of the video,
I'm going to show
you through some of the landing pages,
the structure of how we do them, and how
they could potentially benefit your
business.
Let's get into some of those lead magnets
as far as the squeeze pages and the
landing pages that go for them.
We can quickly go through some of those.
I'll explain the method behind my madness.
Just refreshed the page, 3,998,560.
So by the time Declan's finished the edit,
hopefully it'll be at that elusive four
million. Otherwise, I'm just a fraud,
or I'll have to buy my own mentorship to
get those numbers up. Lovely.
And by the way, this platform here that
you're seeing called Pablo,
there could be some scope in me
guys getting you to use this to host all
of this yourself, because this is where I
host all of the stuff
that I've been showing you before.
But hush.
Okay, let's start here. 30 Days,
30 Insights:
30 Ways to Optimize Your Business.
Any of you that watched the livestream
that I did the other day, you remember me
talking about a time
that I signed up to someone's email list,
52 Ways, 52 Days.
At the end, he went to promote his book.
This is where I just say to people, "Look,
give me your email address." There's no
big page or anything fancy.
It's just me saying,
"Give me your email address.
I'll help you for 30 days." It's like a
value proposition.
Didn't actually have to build anything
or get a graphic designer to make
anything.
I just give value over
that email autoresponder.
So whatever it could be.
You could be a podiatrist helping people
run.
You could be a physio,
golf instructor improving someone's swing.
Pick something that you're really good at
and help people over 30 days.
Average person for this buys on day 19.
Couldn't tell you why.
This is the landing page. And again,
we kind of...
A lot of people in my mentorship,
and I'm copying this.
I did make a mistake on this. Really,
we should change it to be benefit first,
then
how long it is.
So it should be optimize your business in
30 days. I concede.
The only sales page template you'll ever
need.
Because everything on a landing page
should follow a certain procedure.
Again, links in the descriptions.
Copy all of these.
I don't have to oversell this because it's
just a squeeze.
It's, "Hey, this is this. This
is what it is. Do you want it?
Yes or no?" We try to get someone's email
address.
We only need a fraction of what we would
need to get someone's money.
Sell anything to anyone. Subheading.
Use this to generate eight figures in
online sales. Hush. Put your name in,
email.
Here, fancy a constructive roast?
Sign up below.
So if we go to my YouTube,
where's my most recent
roast? [laughs] For this one,
I intentionally went super low
quality, went webcam, went headphones,
did no mic, did it in my
bedroom.
I was just fucking around to see whether
or not it was going to work
better. And let's actually have a look.
It was just chaos.
But you'll notice
that the first link I put there, Weboptin.
Now,
all my revenue isn't going to be on here
because I only started a clean slate
recently. So if we go to Published,
here I can see the actual
revenue that I've got from videos.
16K, 16K, 9K, 8K, 6K. Bloody lovely.
So when people end up putting their stuff
through there, it goes to get sent to me.
I pick them through to the next time.
Like I said,
this versus the 30-day autoresponder,
double the amount of
attributed revenue. Why? No idea.
There's the landing page.
A landing page has to be different to a
squeeze page. Heading,
tells us what it is.
Subheading, context and nuance.
Here we have a VSL, video sales letter.
We always want a bit more information.
So some people,
their mind will be made up
when they get here.
Sorry,
I've got really bad hay fever today.
I haven't been doing cocaine.
Some people see this and go, "Yeah,
I want it." They'll buy.
Some people will watch this video,
they'll buy.
Other people need all the rest of the
information.
They're probably autistic,
and autism loves detail.
They get to the bottom, and they buy.
Little bit of an FAQ. Cool.
You'll notice,
exactly the same for the email marketing
course.
I use dark mode,
mostly because I prefer using dark mode on
my phone and stuff.
Title,
Everyone Talks About Your First $10,000
Month.
Wait Until You Have Your $10,000 Email.
I say this to people all the time.
There is a time coming,
you will make $10,000 from an email.
It just will happen.
I couldn't believe that
when I first heard it, but now, oh,
Pete Schofield.
Some emails will get annoyed
if it doesn't do 10,000.
It's just a matter of time.
Like I say,
there is a certain amount of email
addresses you need to have a
million-dollar database.
Could be 500 for some of you,
it might be 10,000 for
others.
This was just the amount of sales I made
from emails alone.
There's my daily emails, 405,000.
More information.
I want to master email marketing. Lush.
Then I told you about the PT Starter Kit.
Finally, a course
that will answer the question,
how the fuck do I run a better PT
business? Again, PT Starter Kit.
I've done it. I've been it.
Jump two years ahead in your career in
just 30 days.
That is a promise and a half, isn't it?
And again, Short-Form Content Mastery
is that.
I created these things to benefit my
mentorship,
but then I can put them out on the
front end to make sales.
And then here's the business mentorship.
Testimonials.
Eric, like I said before,
he just bought a Lamborghini Urus.
This guy is doing so well,
he has a better car than me.
Love to see it.
And then you get access to everything
else. Like I say, not bad.
And I'll be honest, those of you that
are still watching this video right now,
I'll
actually put a link in the description for
an offer better than that, which I don't
particularly like doing,
but I'm a kind god.
And you can thank Cam for that.
Because I've hired Cam in the Discord,
I'm happier to give a discount because
he's
helping me out. Cool. So these
are some of the landing pages that we run.
So from the satellite courses,
some people buy them, and
if they don't buy on, we
use that revenue to pay for some of the ad
spend that we use to acquire them.
But advertising works a lot better in
these kinds of businesses.
For a PT business, I would not say
that paid ads is your way out.
It's not the way you can buy to not doing
it.
Like I say, even right now,
even with paid ads,
I have to turn up every single
fucking day and claw away being active to
bring business to my business.
If you think you can just put money on
paid ads and walk away, you're naive.
The majority of you,
it's just not going to happen.
Every single flow has email marketing
follow-up emails, and it
is often the emails
that people buy from.
I tried sales calls for a bit, but having
to give the person on the call money,
having to monitor the
quality of the call, I was like,
do you know what?
If people can't watch a video like this
or watch the two and a half hour live
stream we did at the weekend and know
that they want to fucking join,
they can fuck
off. If someone goes,
"I really just need a call before
spending." Fuck
off. Sorry,
I'd rather you just didn't join.
I'd rather just have less money.
I'd rather just not have you two
and a half grand or whatever it
is what we'll be
charging. When this video goes out,
we could even be charging three grand,
four
grand, five grand. Who knows?
Did try using closers in the DMs. It
was all right.
Did 5% to 10% of the revenue.
And as far as hires,
we've got Cam in the Discord,
we've got Declan outside. Ollie
is a YouTube strategist.
You'll be seeing him in the Discord a bit,
actually.
So Ollie isn't hired to work in the
Discord.
He's actually there to help me with ideas
for YouTube.
He gets paid,
and then he also gets a percentage of
anything that we sell from the
video, which is pretty good for him.
He's also going to be a key component in
the YouTube course that we're building out
now. Now,
we are going to charge quite a bit of
money for the YouTube course, but
we will give it to people in the
mentorship for free.
So if you join now,
you will get to get free access to that,
which is pretty cool.
Again, got the Discord.
I'm not going to show you... Actually,
do you know what?
Let's do a bloody another screen recording
because I might even answer some of the
questions while we're here. Okay, so
if we go to Welcome,
there'll be some people
here. Bailey Van. Ooh,
I asked to see some of her stuff, so I
can just go up here.
I teach people how to sell AI digital
products on Etsy.
Very interesting.
So I'll come over here.
I'll have a look at Bailey's stuff.
69,700 subscribers.
She is perfect for this. Here's
my low ticket annual membership sales.
Let's have a look. Ooh. That's on Skool.
Not the biggest fan of Skool,
but she's making 47Gs a month.
Maybe we got a lot of Skool.
You know what I mean?
Very cool. Let's have a little look.
Hi there, and welcome to the AI Design
and Grow Experience, where I- Love
this.
Let's have a look at some of her videos.
Wow. Love that.
My six income streams
that made me $2.3 million at age 40.
Oh, do you know what?
I could be stealing that for the title.
You know what? One day ago as well. Okay.
I like that.
My six income streams. Oh,
I'm stealing that, Bailey.
I'm stealing it.
My one income stream
that's made me a millionaire.
That's very sick.
Straight into analytics. Do you know what?
You might think I'm here to help them.
These people are helping me.
[laughs] These people are helping me.
Love that. Thumbnails, a little bit busy,
but I like it.
Let's go here. Popular.
Income streams that made me...
Okay, so that last video she's done,
if you haven't noticed this already,
is almost
a copy of this outlier.
Income streams that made me 650K last
year, all because
of a $3 digital
product. I like it.
So one thing I want to know is if she gets
analytics from Skool,
so we can see how many visits
over how many conversions.
So the reason we want to know
if we can see the visits
and conversions is, for instance,
if she's got a high conversion rate of,
say
6%, we can go. We just need more traffic.
We just need to send more people here.
We need to talk about it more, improve
and increase the frequency of whatever it
is. However, if the conversion rates
are at 1% and she's
sending thousands of people,
we might need to do something in our power
to increase
the conversion rates by using a better
landing page, for example.
So that's just one interaction I'm going
to have with Bailey over the course of
probably quite a long,
fruition relationship.
But that, let's say for instance,
she does implement a lead page
or a landing
page into her business
and it improves her conversions,
she's going to make the
money that she's given me back,
like $2,500 very quickly.
Especially if she's charging
and making this kind of crazy money
already.
She's already got a YouTube channel that's
crushing. Do you know what I mean?
So, she's already making 50K,
half a mil a year from this.
So these little changes
that I can make to her business
and just smooth it out, can
mean that she can make her money back in
maybe even like a week or two weeks.
They're the businesses
that really excite me. Okay.
Jason was the guy I spoke about with the
gun company.
"We watched this happen from the States.
Minus why we need to protect our
constitutional rights.
Here's my channel." Roaster Weyah,
I think. 15,000 subscribers. Awesome.
Okay. Thumbnails, interesting,
but they work.
That last video killed it, 101,000 views.
This product was illegal, so we fixed it.
Okay, let's go back and compliment him.
Bro, don't think these thumbnails
are as good as
they could be. Some of these videos crush.
Probably because gun people don't care
that much.
Let's get back into it a little bit.
Okay, 192 videos.
Let's look at the most popular. Okay.
These two here work the best,
where it's literally just holding
the thing. 13 years ago as well. Okay,
cool.
So what I'm seeing here is
if we take the last eight
videos,
then we look at the eight most popular
they look very different.
So here's the feedback I'm going to give.
Can you explain to me why your most
popular videos and your most recent
look so different? I know they're old,
but it seems the single
image with simple title does really well.
Did these old videos convert to much
business, I
suppose is the question.
"Welcome to Mountain Tactical,
your ultimate source for
everything Tika.
Whether you're a precision shooter,
hunting enthusiast, or fan of
cool rifles." Tika rifle. What
is a Tika rifle?
Okay.
Beretta Holding Group. Lovely. Okay.
There's a lot of links there.
Four million views though, you know? Okay.
I would love a very simple bio.
"We sell." And I would
love one link, not 13, perhaps to the
store. Is there anywhere that you think
is more
important to send them than website? Okay.
And for us to fully understand this,
we're going downstairs
because I just want you to have a look at
this quickly.
There are only four links here,
but none of them take you to other social
media
accounts.
So I'm going to answer his question the
best way that I know how.
And we're going to do this again,
aren't we, Declan? Do you know why?
Why?
Because it didn't record yesterday.
But it's okay.
We come back the next day with a smile on
our face and we go, "What an opportunity
to do it better." Do you know what else
has happened since yesterday, Declan?
We've hit four million. Thank God.
Do you know what?
By the time this edit's ready,
we could be doing a video on how we made
five
million. But let's get into it.
So old matey boy had 13
links.
Going to explain why that's potentially a
problem.
Now I've actually spoken to him overnight
in the Discord, and he said that the new
person helping him create thumbnails
is an expert,
but I think his thumbnails have
got worse, not better.
But we'll get into that a bit later.
So one thing we need to think about
is traffic.
Traffic is sending people to websites.
If you're actually going to ask me what I
was good at, I wouldn't even say it's
business. I'd say it's traffic.
If you wanted me to run your business,
so many
components of it, I have no idea. HR,
payroll, P&L, no idea.
My job is actually just sending traffic to
websites.
Now,
traffic goes through several different
tiers.
And when we understand this,
I'm going to show you within my business,
it's going
to make so much more sense.
So the easiest way to segment these
is going to be
squeeze, email, landing page.
For the squeeze page, we have 30 days and
30 ways. So that is an autoresponder.
Some of you are thinking about, "Oh,
I've got to build something.
Got to make it." For that,
I just had to write 30 emails.
People sign up to that,
they get an email every single day.
Often people buy on day 19.
We don't know why.
Another squeeze we have is the-
Just on those squeeze pages,
how much time do people spend to make
them?
Is it a lot of effort or
is it a short Kind of thing
How much time and effort should you put
into squeeze page?
It should really just be a heading,
subtitle, probably an image, and then a
sign-up.
A squeeze page should be able to scan
and read in 30 seconds.
A landing page might take a few minutes.
So you could make this in a day,
basically.
Oh, easy. Yeah,
you could pre-write 30 emails in a
document, put them into
your email marketing platform,
then create the squeeze page.
You could collect emails, yeah,
easily in the same day.
Now, the web application,
you will have seen that some of my videos,
even though
they look like they don't do that well,
they only get 3,000, 4,000, 5,000 views,
they still get hundreds of people
that apply for web applications.
When they do that for me to critique their
content, I can't do them all.
I do some, and the ones
that don't get done actually get put into
the
30-day automation. Now, interestingly,
those people attribute
twice the revenue than people
that just go into the 30-day automation.
Why?
I have no idea. I don't know.
Another lead magnet we have is the
high-converting landing page. That
is the sheet that I held up before,
and then
that goes into 11-day automation.
What software would you suggest for the
lead magnets?
Is there a specific one you recommend, or?
So rather than getting caught up in really
complex software, let's say you wanted
to give people a PDF,
or you wanted to send them a lot,
or you wanted something,
whatever. In that first email you send,
you could just give them the Drive,
Dropbox
links.
You could give them anything you want.
So some people are like, "Oh,
I want to create some software" where they
get the
software, and they get this,
they get something else out.
I'm like,
"Or just put it in your first email." So
those guys go into an 11-day
automation. Those people go into 30 days.
The reason we've come down
is because now we're looking at the email
component of
what we're talking about. Now,
the reason that we do this
is to nurture people.
So for us to fully understand this,
and the one thing
that joins these together is
something called an autoresponder.
And that is where you pre-write the amount
of emails so that when someone signs up
to one of your squeeze pages, email one
is sent, wait 24 hours, email two is sent,
wait 24 hours, email three is sent.
So no matter when people join,
they get those emails.
You don't have to manually send them.
They get sent automatically.
Some of you might have realized
that after you buy something,
the next day they
follow up,
or they come back a month later.
Good protein companies,
let's say they sell you a bag of protein
that's got 60
serves in. 60 days after they buy it,
they go, "Hey, you might be running low on
protein.
Do you want to reorder?" These
are all part of what we call
autoresponders.
You have a course about this as well,
right?
Oh, yeah. Oh, God, yeah.
We cover all of this in the mentorship,
and people know
about that.
If they want to learn more, they-
Oh, yeah, they can fucking join, Declan.
We're going to come back to the email
segment in a bit.
But now you need to understand some of
those landing pages
that I sent you before.
So we have Short-Form Content Mastery,
the Business Mentorship,
we have Send Emails
Get Paid, we have PT Starter Kit,
and we have Chatbot and Chill.
So each one of these
is a standalone product with its own
sequence
of title, subheading, VSL,
some of the things
that I showed you before.
So now, some of you
are going to be thinking about what ways
we're going to get
traffic to these. So
when people come into the autoresponders,
they're going to get
promoted into something. Now,
the main thing that makes the most sense
is from
these people to get sold into the Business
Mentorship.
This is where we get the highest return on
investment.
Some people, it's high ticket.
I don't really like the terminologies high
ticket,
low ticket. Then if they do not buy
that after the certain sequence of
those days, we would then try
and sell them Short-Form Content Mastery,
which is
$99. The reason being,
we're not going to make a huge amount of
money from that,
but what we will do
is probably get our money back
that we've spent because
ultimately there is some time, energy,
and effort that's going into this.
But we'll talk about the paid component in
a second.
If they're not going to buy the product
that we want after going through all of
this, the least we can do is get back $99.
So as far as an organic flow, people
are going to get pushed into these.
The other way that people
are going to get pushed into these
is using YouTube as a
source of traffic means
that we can pick certain specific types of
videos.
So what I'll do is I'll go, "Hmm,
what do we want to sell today, Declan?"
If we
want to sell Short-Form Content Mastery,
we'll have a YouTube about it, do a call
to action. Any of the YouTube videos
that I talk about personal training get
sent
to the PT Starter Kit.
Any email marketing videos will get sent
to Send Emails Get
Paid.
So there's always going to be an element
of traffic that can go specifically
to these landing pages.
Are you saying that you structure your
YouTube videos around specifically the
products that you're selling?
Yes. So this video here
is specifically with the outcome of
getting people in the
Business Mentorship.
That's why it's longer.
That's why we're going into more detail.
That's why we're showing them how the
sausage is made because this would be a
lot
of stuff to talk about to just get a $99.
We haven't actually spoken
that much about improving your content.
Most of this is about how to operate your
business because when they join the
Business Mentorship, they get all of this.
So there's no point in us talking about
something as potentially trivial as
Short-Form Content Mastery
when we actually want to get the big sale.
And the people watching along could be
watching along for 45 minutes now.
So they're making a semi-emotional
investment.
So we can determine whether
or not we want to send traffic to squeeze
pages. Now, what we can understand
is out of 100 people, if we ask them to,
maybe 30 will actually go across to those.
But if we send traffic to these pages,
a lot less people are going to be ready to
buy. So it makes sense
that we nurture them through it.
Let's say this level here
is asking someone to come around for
Netflix and chill.
This level here is saying,
"Can I have your number?"
And this level here is, "Can
we go on a date?" Most people want to get
a number, chat for a bit, go on a date,
go on a date, Netflix and chill.
Some people will let you skip stages.
Good question.
Do you just promote one thing?
What you'll notice is
if you go through any of my YouTube
videos, there will often
be four different links at the bottom,
but the one at the top
is the one I want the
sale for most.
But some people just find their way
through it and buy.
For instance,
we did the golf video with Ryan Moak,
and at the end, someone just
bought the Business Mentorship.
We didn't talk about it the whole way
through.
We spoke about golf.
So some people just do that.
YouTube means that you can determine where
you want that traffic to go.
Now, there is another type of traffic,
which I will admit hasn't worked that
well in a lot of my businesses. This
is the only real one that it's worked in.
Someone in the mentorship yesterday
was actually asking about paid ads,
and I was
saying to them, "Look, this
is where a lot of mentorships
and gurus will be like,
'Don't do this. Just spend money.
Send people there.'" The issue is these
people have bought into you,
and they go to these places
when they're ready.
Here,
you're kind of paying to get them to go to
those places.
So the conversion's never going to be as
good on paid ads as they are organic.
Also, I would argue the reason
that my paid ads do so well
is because I understand
organic.
So when we go to do content shoots,
film ads, whatever it is,
we are creating organic content
that we know is going to be good.
We know it's going to work for organic,
so paid is easy. This is the cake.
This is the icing.
So you're saying the fundamentals of
organic content just cross over to paid?
Yeah.
If you can't get people to watch your
content and buy your stuff organically,
why do you think just putting money behind
it's going to help?
This is fundamentals. That's advanced.
So this is the cake.
This is your Victoria sponge.
There's your icing. Icing on its own,
not that nice.
Icing on a cake,
delicious. Now,
we get to determine where our paid ad
spend money goes.
So we don't really do paid ads to YouTube.
It's just not really working
that well to us.
What we do is run some paid ads towards
these squeeze pages.
Is there different platforms you do paid
ads on?
Like Facebook-
Yeah. So Meta does Facebook and Insta.
Google does YouTube For us, Meta, we
are going to expand more into Google,
more into YouTube.
So one person who's crushing at the moment
is Charlie Morgan.
Every time we go watch a YouTube video,
he pops up.
Now, again, with those videos,
you've got to ask yourself,
if I'm going to go to
the club for an hour
and I'm going to pay entry to go into a
club, do I want to go
get as many numbers as I can in that hour,
or do I want to see if I can get laid in
that hour? So a real tactician would say,
"Go get numbers, bro." Because then once
you leave the club, you can work with it.
But if people aren't sure on that night,
you can never contact them again.
So we run paid ads to the 30 days
autoresponder.
We don't run paid ads to the web
application because it doesn't make sense.
But we do run paid ads to the
high-converting landing page.
Then they go into the autoresponders.
Now, once they've gone into these,
some buy, some don't.
But what's good is once you have their
email address, once they've finished that
automation,
you can still broadcast to them.
So the two ways you can email someone
is an autoresponder.
A broadcast is where you just send an
email to everyone on your list.
So the reason we would send an email to
everyone on the list, Black Friday, we
might have loads of dormant leads,
people that originally signed up because
they
wanted to know more,
but they've gone cold.
Then we send them a Black Friday offer,
we can re-engage them.
We might clean the list
if no one buys anything for six months,
but-
How do you clean it? You just-
You just get rid of it.
You put in the conditions.
Someone hasn't opened an email in six
months, delete.
Because then your open rates will increase
as you delete bad leads out.
It's worth to actually keep cleaning out
then.
Cleaning your list keeps your costs down,
probably helps with your deliverability.
If people aren't reading your emails,
you're always going to get scored on
reputation. How many people
are blocking you?
How many people aren't opening your
emails?
How many people are reporting you as spam?
Is it worth learning as well
if you don't have your own private domain?
Oh, yeah. You need your own domain.
Imagine this, people.
Imagine you say, "James,
I'm getting married.
Can you recommend a good wedding
videographer?" I'll go, "Yeah.
Let me get Steve in touch."
And Steve messages you from
stevelovesweddings@gmail.com. No, hold on.
Whether it was
steve@weddingphotography.com,
you would be very differently
portraying that.
When people cold email you trying to sell
stuff and they do it
from a Gmail, you think it's a scammer.
But you think you can do it with your own
fitness business? Ridiculous.
Okay,
so now we can run some paid ads straight
to the landing
pages. Now,
we said this didn't work quite as well
before.
We said that sending people here
is the best way because you can nurture
them.
But it's worth sending some traffic to
these.
Because if that product is $99,
there's no reason that we couldn't spend
$90 acquiring them. But you might go,
"James, why go to all that effort just to
make $9?" Well,
that's because some people will upsell,
and for us, we get about
11%. So we get them for $90. We make $9,
but they
upsell. We suddenly make the full amount.
Some people want to see something
and do it and use it for a while, and then
once they see how good that product is,
they go, "Let me have the whole thing." So
we get a certain amount of business
mentorship sales from upsells from these
satellite courses. And remember,
we didn't build these in the onset to make
money.
We built these for people in the
mentorship to get a better experience.
But if we're going to go to all
that effort, because there
was the insecurities
that business mentorship one wasn't good
enough.
So we added these satellite courses before
re-recording the whole thing.
So you might ask,
why also come here for the people
that don't upsell?
And the question is this. If we
were going to do paid ads and go, "Hi,
my name's
James Smith,
and I want you to give me 30 days so I can
give you 30 ways to improve
your business." It's okay because you're
just asking for that.
But if you think about something I built,
like for instance, PT Starter Kit, the
ads that we have for that,
and you know because you've been on all
the ad shoots.
If you're a personal trainer,
you're never going to get ahead unless you
nail this
one thing, and that's content creation.
So I decided to not only give you
short-form content mastery,
but I've created a
course so that you can understand all the
things you need to do as a personal
trainer in your first year.
That kind of spiel works pretty well
considering that one is $99 as
well. Those paid ads are quite effective.
Do you think it's better to have a paid ad
to a cheaper offering compared to the
whole big-
Well,
paid ads towards a cheap offering being
better depends on the upsell.
Because it also depends how much
that person costs to acquire.
So $99 isn't really revolutionary,
and you asked before about some things
being too cheap,
some things being expensive.
Some people just want to try.
They just want an entrée before ordering a
main course.
And it's a good way for them to get into
the ecosystem, use the platform, see the
content, see what it's about.
I joined someone's content course the
other day, and
the mic that we use upstairs
was on the sofa just lent like
that pointing at
the person. Straight away I thought,
"Am I going to upsell if you couldn't even
hang the mic in the right place?" So you
will notice that the other day,
Monday,
we put something else in the ecosystem.
We created a webinar.
Now,
a webinar is a great way to just create a
product out of thinner air.
So right now we haven't really got a
product.
Oh, we're going to do a webinar,
and it was two hours and 20 minutes.
So what we did for this
was we sent some organic traffic to sign
up.
We sent some paid ads to sign up. Now,
you'll notice that we've put the webinar
in
the email section. The reason being
is the equity in the IP in the
webinar is the amount of email addresses
we got. So we got about 2,500 sign-ups.
So then from the webinar,
we did the live stream on YouTube.
Now, two things happened. First of all,
in the webinar, there's a verbal call to
action to buy the business mentorship,
of which we sold enough to send us over
the
$4 million mark. Now, all the people
that don't buy, we can put into a 30-day
automation. And it's not just
that the webinar wasn't enough
and the 30-day
automation wasn't.
There's something magical about emailing
someone every day.
This means that over the next 30 days,
they might have watched the webinar.
They might be on the fence.
Then over the next month, I email them,
I email them, I
email them. One day,
they lose three clients in a day. Boom,
I'm joining.
They have one video.
They put loads of effort into it.
It bombs. They're joining.
By putting them into an automation after
this, it just keeps them warm so that if
something in their life does happen,
they can make the choice to join.
Would you say the webinar's almost like a
squeeze page or a lead magnet in itself?
It is a lead magnet in itself.
Oh.
It is a form of squeeze, but the main
equity is in the email addresses.
So here we've created
this for you to give us your email.
This we've created for you to give us your
email. Now this-
More often,
or is it like do one every week?
I said this. I actually said to Luke,
"Should we do these more often?" He goes,
"You can't do them too often,
otherwise they're no longer a webinar.
It's just a weekly call." So we need them
to be scarce enough that people want to
join but frequent enough
that you get the revenue.
Adding another 2,500 email addresses to
your ecosystem is great.
Then if they don't buy business mentorship
after a month, and they've gone through
the automation and still not bought,
what do you reckon we could do?
Send them to get a smaller course,
of which some might nibble, of
which some will
upsell. We've spent the money,
and we've sent the organic traffic.
We might as well. And if not,
out of all those people,
we'll put them straight into
another funnel. And also,
these people that watch the webinar,
they might be just
on the fence,
but they might just need a little bit more
emotional pain over the
coming weeks before they join.
Sometimes it takes people a week before
they
actually want to do it.
So then let's say you and I
were working with people in the
mentorship today,
and they've got a problem.
Let's think of a problem you think a
business could have
that works for me in the
mentorship. Well, actually,
so we're about to build the YouTube
course.
So we started building it, and I
was worried it wasn't good enough,
and we're
calling it the Silver Play Button.
I've also got Ollie to be working on this
full-time with me.
So we've created another YouTube course.
We're going to call it the Silver Play
Button.
It's going to be everything you need to
get your silver play button.
And I'm thinking we're going to sell this
at maybe $1,000.
Then I'm actually thinking we're going to
offer that into people in the business
mentorship. Everyone that's in there now,
we'll give it to you for free.
But in the future,
as they get to the checkout, we will say,
"Do you want to grow
your YouTube at the same time?"
And we'll maybe bolt it on for $1,000
or $500,
something like that
And I'm actually thinking of hiring new
employees that just
help with that YouTube course. Then also,
if some people's business is fine, but
they just want to grow their YouTube,
this can be a standalone course.
Now, we can then run paid ads.
My name's James Smith, and I've nearly got
three silver play buttons.
And it'll be really good
when we do have three silver
play buttons.
You might think now would be a good time
for me to ask you to
subscribe,
but I don't ask people to subscribe.
I'm not your fucking dad.
If you don't want to subscribe,
that's fine.
If you just want to watch my content,
I don't need you to be following my
channel.
I actually think people asking people to
subscribe is beggy and pathetic.
We'll put that on the course as well.
So we're going to run paid ads to that.
And again, because that course is $1,000,
we could spend $200 acquiring someone, or
just 800 up.
It just depends on how many members of
staff we have.
But then now this is here,
it unlocks a whole new potential of lead
magnets.
So we could create a lead magnet on
thumbnails.
We could create an AI bot
that helps people with titles, LUT
and colors.
Oh, okay. Art studio.
Editing.
So these can be all potential lead
magnets.
And what we'll do is we will send organic
traffic to all of these people.
"Hey, guys. If you enjoyed this video
and you want to know how to create title
and
thumbnails like us,
go to this link." "Hey, guys.
If you like the color grading in this
video, head to this." Actually, you'll
probably say, "No, I want that,"
but it's fine.
"Hey, if you've ever wondered what
are the studio settings you need to have
for
your upload to do well, do this.
It's completely free." Then also,
we can start
allocating paid ads into
that ecosystem as well to get people from
there.
Then what we're probably going to do there
is create a brand-new YouTube
nurture system,
and we could call it YouTube Mastery,
and it could be, pick a
number, random number, 24 days.
Do longer email automation perform better
than shorter ones?
Yeah. Sometimes,
because some people doing longer
automations drag out the stuff,
and they don't go to it quite as much.
I'm not sure would be the answer,
because sometimes you can just hit them in
seven
days. Boom, boom, boom. Your best stuff.
By an hour, fuck off, I'm gone.
Sometimes if you hit them for too long,
they might be like, "Oh, maybe I can do
this on my own." So I'm not actually sure.
So a lot of what we do
is just going with it.
Like this video, before we started it,
we just looked at the title and thumbnail.
We planned this in five minutes.
And then from there,
we would upsell them into the
YouTube course. Then
when we get people
that grow their YouTube, what do we
do? We make content about it.
With the content about it,
we connect a mini chat
chatbot to one of these free resources.
Out of the people that do really well,
we create a paid ads.
Like when Doc started smashing it
and we're in LA.
You say to me, "James,
let's go outside and make a video about
it." Still to this
day, one of our highest-performing ads.
Then people start buying the YouTube
course.
Then people that buy the YouTube course,
from seeing all of that stuff, we could
then say to them, "Hey, do you know what?
Do you want some help with your business?
Check out the business mentorship." They
can start coming back into here.
We can get more money from them,
but at the same time,
we could give them a better
offer as well because they're already
invested into that.
The ecosystem just keeps evolving
and growing based on the products
that we do.
Then probably about time,
some point next year,
we'll do Business Mentorship 3.0.
Because the reason we need to reiterate
every year is I am learning so much.
And I'll be honest with you,
I knew quite a bit about business,
about all of this.
But since doing this for the last two
years,
I would have almost paid $4 million to
learn what I've learned, but actually,
I got to earn it.
Even though I don't actually get to keep
that much of it.
But these are the things
that we're working with, with businesses.
Does any of that not make sense to you?
It all makes sense,
but I want to ask you this.
Probably a lot of people in your
mentorship have coaching-style businesses
where
they might do a call like you recommended
for me.
How would this funnel differ if they
were offering calls rather than selling a
digital product?
Okay. So how would this differ if you
were just selling calls?
So you're thinking about your stuff.
If we're using Calendly to do lessons on
whatever it is, maybe-
Mm-hmm
... video editing, in my situation.
Would I have a landing page?
Okay.
So we're going to use Declan example here.
So you look at all of this
and you're like,
"I've only got a YouTube channel."
Because I want to do this eventually,
but I think when you said it mentioned to
me
before to do the course, I was like,
"Hang on a minute.
That's a way I could start making money
now without having to build this whole
course." So it kind of got me excited.
Let's use you as an example.
Yeah.
So Declan. What I don't like here
is Declan, I'm setting you up to leave
me here. Don't laugh.
I have to get Etienne back.
Okay, so at the moment,
you've got no landing page,
you've got no infrastructure,
whatever. And we were saying
that you need to create a Calendly. Cool.
So you like the idea of making $200 an
hour.
Isn't that much more than I pay you,
by the way? Especially some weeks.
So you've got that.
Your traffic at the moment
is to send people to that.
And it'd probably be a verbal call to
action. All right.
So you're saying where does everything
else sit in the ecosystem?
Well,
I would say we should create a squeeze
here.
I reckon we could call it Nine Biggest
Editing Mistakes.
Subheading, How to Fix It.
So I would say color grading
tips can be the solution,
but not the problem.
So if I say color grading tips-
That's fair
... people could go, "My colors
are fine." But so you go, "Oh, by the way,
if you
want to know the nine biggest editing
mistakes and how to fix it,
click the link in
the bio." So now we're having one paid,
one free.
You'll even notice
that in my YouTube bios,
I say paid things, free things.
I make it really clear to people.
Are you here to buy, or
are you here to get
something for free? Now,
email number one of this could be your
colors.
If you started talking about colors in
content, they might just get bored
and fuck
off. But here you go,
"I know you don't want to hear this,
but your color grading
is killing your edits." And
that becomes the first place
that you start positioning
it.
So what I've got so far,
because I've written a few,
I'm using the LUT as the lead
magnet, and then the first email
is telling them how to actually apply the
LUT
properly, because most people do it wrong.
Are you confident-
Most people make the same mistakes
...
that every single person that's perfect
for your business knows what a LUT is?
So everyone that watches the color grading
videos knows what a LUT is, yes.
Okay.
Something that most people sell.
I don't see anyone giving away for free.
People want LUTs.
I'll give it for free to use to get their
email address, to then
send them emails about color grading tips-
Okay
... problems.
I hope to then get them to either book in
a call or buy the course.
Cool. Okay.
So this one may be not perfect,
but definitely keep it in there.
You could all call
that Nine Biggest Color Mistakes,
How to Fix It. Whatever.
Then another could be free LUT.
But with this as well, keep in mind-
So with that free LUT now,
I've got about 1,400 email addresses.
So it's been performing really-
Okay. So when they got that free LUT,
how many emails did you send
afterwards? No follow-up, nothing.
It's like you meeting a girl on the dance
floor, going, "Lovely to meet you
tonight." And then never messaging her
again.
I was kind of like, "Oh,
I want to write the emails first."
And just been lazy,
really.
Well, what you can do is you can,
you're probably going to want to create it
first.
Put together your autoresponder.
Be done in a day.
Not today because you'll be busy with this
edit.
Pick maybe 11, 15, something like that.
Don't even tell them they're going to get
them.
Just say,
"Hope you're enjoying the free LUT."
"Here's how to make the most out of it."
"Here's how to make the most out of it.
These are the films it's for. This
is this.
By the way, do you want to book in a call?
Go here." First two,
let them have for free. Send them here.
Then over time, you're going to learn,
learn.
For that Calendly,
would I have a landing page as well,
or just a link?
No, because in this,
at the PS of your email, you just say,
"If you want to talk to
me, it's $200 an hour.
Here's the link." You don't need landing-
In the email or to here to-
No, put it in. Well, the thing is,
if they can't afford it in the email,
they won't
click. But if they can't afford it
and they get to Calendly,
they're still not
going to click But you could also say to
someone as well, "These calls are
currently half price,
only $200." The language in
which you say it can make it
better. Then you could say to yourself,
after you've done 20 calls,
you're going to
build your first product.
Because you're giving away the lot for
free, right?
Yeah.
So you might want,
I'm not sure what your first product would
be.
Color grading course. Then basically,
those call to actions just turn into that.
Then what you can do from here is,
once people are buying your course from
the
emails,
you're now making money without having to
give people any of your time.
But then people that have bought your
product, "Hey, if this is too much,
you can
book in a call." But you're now going to
need to make this much nicer.
Because the reason this needs to become
more expensive is you don't want people to
book in calls when you've got a product.
You want people to buy the product.
Yeah.
Because ultimately,
you want to make money without having to
service the clients
all yourself.
So you mentioned before,
the empty diary effects.
How would that refer to actually selling
calls?
Would I want to only do set amounts of
time when I'm available or-
You could even say here in your calendar,
"I can only do 5:00 and 6:00 PM
Sydney time because I'm working with James
Smith on progress." Yeah.
And then people go, "Oh, I follow
that guy.
Oh,
this is his editor." You know what I mean?
You're like,
"Sorry for working for one of the most
successful content creators
full time, but outside of that,
you can book in."
And you could even put in it,
"PS,
please don't tell James I'm doing this."
You know what I mean?
Be like, "James pays me really well.
I'm doing these for you.
He's getting slower edits because of it."
Then
you'd create,
you remember you wanted to have some kind
of community as well.
So say you create a Discord.
Now your pricing for the product will
determine
whether or not you're going to be super
active in this.
But from your Discord,
you'll learn loads about what people want
suddenly.
And for anyone wanting to build a product
after running a coaching business, in
terms of pricing it,
you mentioned before about your prices
depending on demand.
Can you go a little bit more into detail
about that?
If you're selling that
and this Discord's getting really fucking
busy, it's
probably too cheap. If you-
From a startup rate to sell a course,
what? 100 bucks?
200 bucks?
I'd go just $99.
Just pretty average industry rate.
It's much easier to put prices up than it
is to pull them down.
Pull the price down, people go-
So start cheap, build demand,
then raise it.
Because if you start at 200
and then it's a bit quiet
and you sell for 99, all
those people that joined early,
your red-hot leads are going to be fucked.
Start low. You're better off.
So like I said, my business membership
was $800 when
I started. It's way too cheap,
way too underpriced.
I was giving people way too much of my
time, but you need to do that to get to a
position to put your price up.
And then as you build out your product,
you might
then,
let's say you're making really good cash
on top of what I pay you.
You could then explore paid.
And then suddenly you could be getting
money that
you're earning from me,
putting $1,000 in there,
and you could be making 1,500
in that. And that would be a ROAS 1.5,
return on ad spend.
If you spend 1,000, you get 1.5. On
that video that we did with
Doc in LA, in the garden,
we got a ROAS of 5.6.
So for every dollar we spent,
we made $5.60.
Doc, if you're watching this,
you're welcome. Links in the description.
Going to be limited on the amount of
business membership people
that we could take
in. They're all the products.
I've actually just shown you exactly how
the business
works. If you enjoyed this, that's great.
If you still want more information
and you want to tune into
that live stream that
I did, it is two hours
and 22 minutes long.
So only click this here
if you have two hours available to you.
If not, that's how the sausage is made.
Join this so I can hire another
videographer because it looks like Declan
wants
out. Bye-bye.